## Kechun Liu

Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science & Engineering, University of Washington, Box 352355, Seattle, WA 98195-2355

**1** (206)-586-4945

kechun@cs.washington.edu

https://kechunl.github.io/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/kechun-liu-4227a21a0/

#### Research Interest

I am a fourth-year Ph.D. student in the GRAIL lab at the University of Washington, Seattle, advised by Prof. Linda Shapiro. My research interests are in the area of generative models, representation learning, real-world computer vision tasks, and medical image analysis.

## **Education**

Overall GPA: 3.87/4.0

Overall GPA: 3.73/4.0 (Rank 20/216)

## **Publications**

- **Liu**, **K.**, Jiang, Y., Choi, I., & Gu, J. (2023). Learning image-adaptive codebooks for class-agnostic image restoration. *arXiv preprint arXiv:2306.06513*.
- **Liu**, K., Li, B., Wu, W., May, C., Chang, O., Knezevich, S., ... Shapiro, L. (2023). Vsgd-net: Virtual staining guided melanocyte detection on histopathological images. In *Proceedings of the ieee/cvf winter conference on applications of computer vision* (pp. 1918–1927).
- Nofallah, S., Shapiro, L. G., Wu, W., **Liu**, **K.**, Ghezloo, F., & Elmore, J. (2022). Automated analysis of whole slide digital skin biopsy images. *Frontiers in Artificial Intelligence*, 209.
- **Liu**, **K.**, Mokhtari, M., Li, B., Nofallah, S., May, C., Chang, O., ... Shapiro, L. (2021). Learning melanocytic proliferation segmentation in histopathology images from imperfect annotations. In *Proceedings of the ieee/cvf conference on computer vision and pattern recognition* (pp. 3766–3775).
- Zong, Z., Feng, J., **Liu**, **K.**, Shi, H., & Li, Y. (2019). Deepdpm: Dynamic population mapping via deep neural network. In *Proceedings of the aaai conference on artificial intelligence* (Vol. 33, pp. 1294–1301).

# Research Experience

### **Ongoing Research**

2023.6 − 2023.9 ♦ Software Engineer Intern

Rivian, Infotainment team.

• **NeRF on Fisheye Camera**: Perform thorough analysis and experiments on applying NeRF to fisheye camera data. Work on NeRF with noisy/unknown camera pose. Work on speeding up NeRF training.

## Research Experience (continued)

2019.7 - present

#### **⋄** Research Assistant

Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science and Engineering, Advisor: Linda Shapiro In-depth knowledge in deep learning (DL) and statistical machine learning (ML). Expertise in delivering ML technologies and image processing skills in curating medical image dataset based on domain knowledge. I'm currently pursuing 3 directions:

- Melanocyte Detection on Skin Biopsy Images: Propose a GAN-based detection model to detect certain types of cells on histopathological images. The model can produce reliable virtual staining and cell detection results which achieves the state-of-the-art performance. [paper]
- Segmenting Melanocytic Proliferations on Skin Biopsy Images: Propose a melanocytic proliferation segmentation framework by leveraging noisy and sparse labels. Achieved state-of-the-art performance on this specific task. [paper]
- **Graph-based Learning in Melanoma Diagnosis**: Build hierarchical cell-to-tissue graph using melanocytes and non-melanocytes features. Train a graph convolutional network to learn melanoma diagnosis. (Ongoing)

#### **Previous Research**

2022.6 - 2022.12

#### ♦ Research Intern

Sensebrain Technology, Advisor: Inchang Choi, Jinwei Gu

- Low-light Portrait Enhancement on Mobile Devices: Train deep learning models to enhance low-light portraits in Bayer format. Integrate the models to mobile device camera pipeline.
- Real-World Blind Super-Resolution: Work on class-agnostic image restoration via adaptive codebooks. Perform thorough data and model analysis. (Paper published in ICCV2023) [paper][github]

2020.7 - 2020.9

## ♦ Sedeen Viewer Plugins for Cancer Diagnosis

Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science and Engineering, Advisor: Linda Shapiro
Built plugins in Sedeen Viewer, a whole slide image viewer, for cancer diagnosis. The backend
and frontend are Python and C++ respectively. [website] [github]

2018.11 - 2019.5

#### ♦ Unsupervised Multimodal MRI Segmentation of Stroke Lesion

MMDP Lab, Advisor: Weibei Dou

Proposed an unsupervised segmentation method based on multimodal brain magnetic resonance images (MRI) of chronic stroke patients to segment stroke lesions including both ischemic and chronic stroke.

2018.7 - 2018.9

### ♦ Conronary Calcium Segmentation on Dual Energy CT Images

The Li Laboratory at Cedars-Sinai and UCLA, Advisor: Debiao Li, and Yibin Xie Worked on the segmentation and sub-voxel resolution algorithms to extract coronary calcified plaques in dual-energy CT images.

2017.11 - 2018.7

#### ♦ DeepDPM: Dynamic Population Mapping via Deep Neural Network

The FIB Lab at Tsinghua University, Advisor: Yong Li

Proposed the idea to generate dynamic population distributions in full-time series. Designed DeepDPM, an overall model that describes both spatial and temporal patterns based on coarse data and point of interest information. [paper][5]

# Teaching Experience

## **Academic Service**

♦ **Reviewer**, IEEE/CVF Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)

# **Awards**

2018 Outstanding Student Award, Electronic Engineering, Tsinghua University.

♦ **ICBC Scholarship**, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China.

2017 **Jiang Nanxiang Scholarship**, Tsinghua University.

2016 • National Scholarship, the government of China.

# Skills

English, Mandarin Chinese.

Programing

 $\diamond \quad \text{Python, C/C++, MATLAB, shell scripts, JavaScript, R, Verilog} \\$ 

Technology

♦ PyTorch, LaTeX, Tensorflow, OpenCV

Relevant Coursework

Computer Vision, Deep Learning, Image Processing, Data Visualization, Statistical Learning, Data Structure, Stochastic Modeling, Machine Learning, Probability, Linear Algebra, Calculus.